(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-26T13:11:44.850867",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Today...
Raora's Birthday
Begins
Ah...
Oh my god, that was a good nap.
Wait... That's not my room?
Why- why am I not watching right now? How did I end up here?
A white canvas? Huh? What is this? Why- why is there a white canvas in here?
Wait, where- where is my room? Huh?
Tsuttino! Thank god you're here!
Oh, this- this place is so scary! Tsuttino, where are we? Tsuttino? Tsuttino?!
What happened to you?
Come here, don't worry, I got you. You're kind of heavy though.
Don't worry, Tsuttino, I got you. We need to find a way out, okay?
We're gonna find a way out.
Where- where should we go? Wait, what is a portal now?
You open it? No?
Fine, I guess we should go in there. Maybe we're gonna wake up, maybe I'm still dreaming.
Okay, I say let's go! You are kind of heavy though.
ローリーガールは いつまでも
For lonely girls, it's always the same,
届かない夢見て
Dreaming dreams that don't come true
騒ぐ頭の中を 掻き回して、
And churning through the clamor in their heads,
掻き回して。
churning.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、
A lonely girl mutters "I'm fine,"
言葉は失われた？
Have words failed her?
もう失敗、もう失敗。
A failure, a failure.
間違い探しに終われば、また回るの！
Obsessing over her mistakes makes everything spin again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、少女は言う
"I'll roll along today," the girl said,
少女は言う 言葉に意味を奏でながら！
breathing life into the words!
「もう良いかい？」
"How about now?"
「まだですよ、まだまだ先は見えないので。息を止めるの、今。」
"Not yet, we still can't see what's ahead. Hold your breath, for now."
ローリングガールの 成れの果て
This is how it ends for a rolling girl,
届かない、向こうの色
Unable to reach the colors on the other side.
重なる声と声を 混ぜあわせて、混ぜあわせて。
The overlapping voices blend together, blend together.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
She mutters, "I'm fine,"
言葉は失われた。
But the words fail her.
どうなったって良いんだってさ、間違いだって起こしちゃおうと
Not caring how it ends, an upward climb that invites mistakes!
誘う、坂道。
One more time, one more time.
もう一回、もう一回。
"Please, get me rolling,"
「私をどうか転がして」と 少女は言う
the girl said, the girl said,
少女は言う 無口に意味を重ねながら！
Carrying her burden through silence!
「もう良いかい？」
"How about now?"
「もう少し、もう何か見えるだろうと。息を止めるの、今。」
"Just a little more, it should be here soon. So I'm holding my breath, just now."
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、少女は言う
"I'll roll along again today," the girl said,
少女は言う 言葉に笑みを奏でながら！
breathing laughter into the words!
「もう良いかい？もう良いよ。」
"How about now? Ok, you can look."
「そろそろ君も疲れたろうね。」
"You must be exhausted too, right?"
息を止めるの、今。
Stop breathing, now.
So, everyone!
Kon-santini!
Hi!
It's me, Raora Panthera
from Hololive English Justice!
Rawr!
Because it means...
Big stage!
What is this place? And why are we here?
And also, what day is it?
What... what day is it?
Is it... is it?
Is it my birthday?!
Yay!
Thank you everyone for being here in this special day.
I'm so happy to see everyone!
So, so, so, so, so! Hi everyone!
And talking about my birthday, I have a special hashtag for today, which is #Raorabday2026. Woah!
So everyone, make sure if you want to share some screenshots and you want to share some comments on social media,
make sure to use this hashtag.
Thank you so much!
Oh, but maybe now we should take a look at this stage. Woah!
It's so... it's so big, isn't it? It's a little bit like... it looks like really dreamy.
Like, it seems like we are in a dream.
Maybe... maybe I'm sleeping?
Woah! Woah! It's like... surrealism kind of thing.
What... what is this place?
Wait, am I... Woah! Woah!
Huh? Huh? Huh? Huh?
My... my idol outfit?
What? Huh? What?
Why is my idol outfit now... maybe that means I should sing more?
Well, might as well.
So please, listen to my songs!
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promises we exchanged,
目を閉じ確信する
I close my eyes to affirm it.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I will shake off the overwhelming darkness to move forward.
進むよ
I will keep moving forward.
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I ever be able to see the lost future...
私ここでまた見ることができるの
from here again?
溢れ出した不安の影を何度も裂いて
Shattering the overflowing shadows of anxiety again and again,
この世界歩き進むよ
I'll walk forward through this world.
とどどなく刻まれた時は今始まり告げ
Time now begins to tick away incessantly,
変わらない思いをのせ閉じられた扉開けよう
Let's open the closed door while carrying our unchanging feelings.
目覚めた心は
My awakened heart
走り出した未来を描くため
started running to draw a future.
難しい道で立ち止まっていても
Even if I come to a halt on a tough road,
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っていてくれる
the beautiful blue sky is always waiting for me.
だから怖くない
That's why I'm not afraid.
もう何があっても挫けない
I won't give up no matter what happens.
振り返れば仲間がいて
When I looked back, my friends were there,
気がつけば優しく包まれていた
Before I knew it, I was surrounded by kindness.
何もかもが歪んだ世界で
In a world where everything was distorted,
唯一信じられるここが救いだった
this was the only place I could believe in that saved me.
喜びも悲しみもわけあえば強まる想い
My feelings will become stronger if we share joy and sadness.
この声が届くのならきっと奇跡はおこせるだろう
If this voice reaches you, I'm sure a miracle will happen.
きっと奇跡は起こせるだろう
I'm sure a miracle will happen.
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to be sure
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the closing-in darkness and move forward
いつになればなくした未来を私ここでまた見ることができるの？
When will I be able to see the lost future here once again?
溢れ出た不安の影を何度も裂いてこの世界歩んでいこう
Let's keep walking through this world, tearing through the overflowing shadows of anxiety over and over
とめどなく刻まれた時は今始まり告げ
Time, ticked away without end, now announces a beginning
変わらない思いをのせ
Carrying unchanging feelings
閉ざされた扉開けよう
Let's open the closed door
目覚めた心は走り出した未来を描くため
My awakened heart began to run, in order to paint the future
壊された世界でさまよって私は
Wandering in a broken world, I was...
引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
drawn in as if guided there
目覚めた心は走り出した未来を描くため
My awakened heart began to run, in order to paint the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I come to a halt on a difficult road
空はきれいな青さでいつでも待っていてくれる
The beautiful blue sky always waits for me
だから怖くない
That's why I'm not afraid
もう何があっても挫けない
I won't be disheartened anymore no matter what happens
振り返れば仲間がいて
When I looked back, my friends were there
気づけば優しく包まれてた
Before I knew it, I was surrounded by kindness
ずっと明日待って
Always waiting for tomorrow
Yay! Happy birthday!
Happy birthday, Raora!
Thank you, Kronii! Thank you!
I'm so excited for you!
It's your first 3D birthday live! It is!
And look at us with our outfits,
we're so pretty!
We are so gorgeous!
I'm so cool!
You are!
I am so cool!
And you know, because you're so cool, I want to give you a beautiful color that I think would suit you.
Me?
Yes. Which color? Pink? Is it going to be pink?
Um, it's... If you look at your eyes, your beautiful yellow eyes...
They have curiosity and playfulness.
And I think it suits you, and so I would like to give this color...
this beautiful color around us.
Which color?
Are you colorblind?
You're not supposed to bully me on my birthday! You're supposed to be nice to me!
And I made your beautiful yellow eyes...
Ah...
It's... You're my birthday insider...
instead of giving me a gift, and you come here, you sing, and thanks with me, and then you just start bullying me.
You know what, get out of here.
I complimented you! It's golden! Golden eyes! Is that beautiful?
So, what, what does it mean? Why, why did you give this color to me?
I... like...
I just said curiosity and playfulness...
Wait, wait, wait, what about you? I was listening to you!
You were paying attention to me! You don't care about me!
My teeth!
You talk too much, my teeth—
I think you should keep up your dream.
I have a question. Okay, I have an answer!
Like, I was expecting blue coming from you.
Ah
Why are you making me laugh?
Is it because of the yellow?
It's... It's your...
It's just this everything is so beautiful.
You're obsessed with my eyes, and
your eyes are so beautiful.
I was expecting more like a blue, because I thought you were like...
sad and see...
Well, you don't have a blue color scheme in your...
Oh.
Yeah, but you, you are blue.
Yeah, but it's because I give you blue.
Oh, thank you.
Yeah.
What does that mean?
Loneliness?
Sadness? Fear? Maybe?
Oh.
That's why would you give that to me?
Because I thought you liked me. I like you.
You, you invited me...
all the way here.
And you give me with this beautiful color and you give me blue.
And you're so pretty like blue.
Yeah.
And you're so pretty. Oh, stop.
You stop!
No, you stop!
Stop!
You know what? We can maybe blend blue and pink together to get purple.
Purple.
Yeah.
Never mind.
What does purple mean?
What does purple mean? I don't know. We'll find out.
Oh.
Whoa, purple! You just spoiled it.
Well, we'll find out, I guess.
To be continued, everyone.
So keep watching our... My, my, my... No, our.
That's not your birthday, it's my birthday.
It is your birthday.
It is my birthday.
It is my birthday, so we're gonna keep watching everyone. We're gonna... I'm gonna keep singing and dancing for you, okay?
Whoa!
And be sure to use her hashtag, okay?
Yes!
Hell yeah!
Raorabbday2026!
Ta-da! Ta-da!
Oh, also thank you, Kronii, for coming.
Oh, yeah, you're welcome.
I forgot to thank you.
Oh, yeah, thank you for having me.
Thank you for singing and dancing with me. It was so fun!
Yeah!
Okay, keep up the good work.
Keep- keep the good work.
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Wooh!
And go! Ta-da! Ta-da!
左手に隠した 願いは願いのままで
Hidden in my left hand, wishes remain as they are,
覚えない夢(ゆめ)見てた
Dreaming of an endless dream.
右手には空(から)の記憶 誰も知らない世界の果て
In my right hand, memories of a shell,
やまなみ雨にうたれていた
being struck by the never-ending rain.
守りたいものを守れる強さ
Strength to protect what I want to protect,
それを信じられなくなる弱さ
weakness that makes it hard to believe in it.
すべてを受け入れて 未来(あした)を探す
Accepting everything, searching for tomorrow.
Brave shine
手を伸ばせばまだ Stay the night
if I reach out my hand, there's still Stay the night,
傷だらけの夜 You save my life
a night full of scars, You save my life.
かざした刃の先に想いを重ねた
Layering feelings at the tip of the raised blade,
祈りは時を超えて Your brave shine...
prayers transcend time, your brave shine...
光ることも忘れた 青い星が残していく
Forgot to shine, the blue star leaves behind.
消えない影見てた すれ違う赤の軌道
Watching the unerasable shadow, the passing red trajectory.
何も知らない子供のままで
Like a child who knows nothing,
明けない夜を彷徨(さまよ)っていた
wandering through the endless night.
失くせないものを失くした弱さ
Weakness of losing what can't be lost,
何も信じられなくなる脆さ
losing faith in everything.
立てなくなっても 運命(さだめ)は進む
Even if the darkness doesn't stand, fate moves forward.
Break down
崩れ落ちていく星座が
the crumbling constellations,
傷つけあう夜 You're breaking dawn
nights where we hurt each other, you're breaking dawn.
交わした約束(ことば)の中に
In the exchanged words,
独りを支えた確かな理想(ゆめ)を添えて...
supporting one another, accompanied by a certain dream...
守りたいものを守れるのなら
If I can protect what I want to protect,
すべてを受け入れて 未来(あした)を探す
accepting everything, searching for tomorrow.
夜明けを灯す Brave shine
Lighting up the dawn, Brave shine.
手を伸ばせばまだ Stay the night
If I reach out my hand, there's still Stay the night,
傷だらけの夜 You save my life
a night full of scars, You save my life.
重ねた涙の果てに 光を見つけた
Finding light at the end of shed tears,
祈りは時を超えて My brave shine...
prayers transcend time, my brave shine...
光ることも忘れた 青い星が残していく
Hikaru koto wa wasureta, aoi hoshi ga nokoshiteku
消えない影見てた すれ違う赤の軌道
Kienai kage miteta, surechigau aka no kiseki
何も知らない子供のままで
Nani mo shiranai kodomo no mama de
明けない夜を彷徨っていた
Akenai yoru o samayotteita
失くせないものを失くした弱さ
Nakusenai mono o nakushita yowasa
何も信じられなくなる脆さ
Nani mo shinjirarenaku naru morosa
立てなくなっても 運命は進む
Tatenaku natte mo sadame wa susumu
Break down
崩れ落ちていく星座が
Kuzure ochite iku seiza ga
傷つけあう夜 You're breaking dawn
Kizutsukeau yoru You're breaking dawn
交わした約束の中に
Kawashita kotoba no naka ni
独りを支えた確かな理想を添えて...
Hitori o sasaeta tashika na yume o soete...
左手に隠した
Hid in my left hand
願いは願いのままで
The wish remains just a wish
覚えない夢見てた
I was seeing an unwaking dream
右手には空の記憶
In my right hand is an empty memory
誰も知らない世界の果て
At the end of a world no one knows
やまない雨にうたれていた
I was being beaten by a ceaseless rain
守りたいものを守れる強さ
The strength to protect what I want to protect
それを信じられなくなる弱さ
The weakness of losing belief in it
すべてを受け入れて
Accepting it all
未来を探す
And searching for tomorrow
守りたいものを守れるのなら
If I can protect what I want to protect
すべてを受け入れて
I accept it all
明日を探す
And search for tomorrow
夜明けを灯す
I will light up the dawn
Brave shine
手を伸ばせばまだ
If I still reach out my hand
Stay the night 傷だらけの夜
In this night covered in wounds
You save my life 重ねた涙の果てに
At the end of the overlapped tears
光を見つけた
I found the light
祈りは時を超えて
The prayer will go beyond time
My brave shine...
Happy Birthday Raora! Happy Birthday! Happy Birthday!
時間だよ メタボ
Time to keto!
Shall we introduce ourselves?
Of course! Please do!
自己紹介をお願いします。
Please introduce yourselves.
自己紹介でオッケー？はい、ぜひ！
Introductions are okay? Yes, please!
はい、こんぺこ、ホロライブ4期生の、あ、えっと、オールド先輩の...
Hi, Konpeko, Hololive 4th Gen... ah, wait, Old senpai's...
え、とかの先輩のです！
Ah, Toko-senpai's!
とかの先輩？いぇい、いぇい、いぇい！とこ先輩、いぇい、いぇい、いぇい！
Toko-senpai? Yay, yay, yay! Toko-senpai, yay, yay, yay!
とこ先輩！とこ先輩！え、オールド先輩か？
Toko-senpai! Toko-senpai! Eh, Old senpai?
Really? え、ちょっと待って！
Really? Eh, hold on!
カリオペ is only a little bit younger in that case then... とか言うな！ What?
Calliope is only a little bit younger in that case then... Don't say that! What?
オッケー、ファイン。ハロー、皆さん！
Okay, fine. Hello, everyone!
オールド先輩、森カリオペです！イェーイ！From Hololive English Myth!
Old senpai, Mori Calliope! Yay! From Hololive English Myth!
What's up, fellow pink? Fellow pink!
イェーイ！Pink is powerful! え、とかさま、you're also pink?
Yay! Pink is powerful! Eh, Toko-sama, you're also pink?
It is pink. We kind of have different shades of pink, right?
Yeah, different shades of pink, right?
Yeah, the colors are so important in this life, so we must say that this is the pink team, right? ... Pink team! Pink-purple team! Yeah, pink-purple team, please!
Nice, wonderful!
But you know, the lighting actually, when we were singing the song that we just sang a moment ago, was blue. Yeah, it was blue.
It was pretty, right? Look at that.
What kind of emotion do you think the blue represents? どんな感情？ Blue. Blue.
What kind of emotion do you think the blue represents? What kind of emotion? Blue. Blue.
ブルーは結構寂しいとか... そうね。ちょっとそういう悲しいみたいなイメージはあるけど...
Blue is quite lonely... True. It has a bit of a sad image...
でも綺麗なイメージもあるよ。うん。 That's also some beautiful, sad, lonely, also beautiful.
But it also has a beautiful image. Yeah. That's also some beautiful, sad, lonely, also beautiful.
Well, for Calli, I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? 怖さ。
Well, for Calli, I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? Fear.
ちょっと怖い、right? But you know, emotions are beautiful, right?
A bit scary, right? But you know, emotions are beautiful, right?
感情がめっちゃ美しいと思う。ね？
I think emotions are super beautiful. Right?
So positive, negative, either way, I think colors are really beautiful. I agree with you.
And you know, even if sometimes we are fear and we are scared of doing something, maybe maybe we should overcome, we should do our best to, you know, 怖くても頑張らないといけないね。
And you know, even if sometimes we are fear and we are scared of doing something, maybe maybe we should overcome, we should do our best to, you know, even if it's scary, we have to do our best.
例えば、stageでtogether, speaking Japanese, it's not so scary.
For example, being on stage together, speaking Japanese, it's not so scary.
You just got to try your best and throw your fears away. 怖くないよ。 -> How do you overcome? We just sang...
You just got to try your best and throw your fears away. It's not scary. -> How do you overcome? We just sang...
Brave Shine! Brave Shine! We just sang.
That's such a good song. Uh, it's very fitting. Right? Yeah, fight your fears. 怖くないね。
That's such a good song. Uh, it's very fitting. Right? Yeah, fight your fears. It's not scary.
勇気持って、courage. And uh, yeah, challenge your dreams.
Have courage. And uh, yeah, challenge your dreams.
Yeah, but fears are also part of our life, right? Like maybe if we're not if we don't feel the fear, then how can we overcome? Like how can we do how to say, like
I don't know the words. Like, how can we challenge our past self and do our best every single day, right?
怖くなかったら、まあチャレンジじゃないよね。うん、うん、確かにね。
If it wasn't scary, then it wouldn't really be a challenge. Yeah, yeah, true.
怖かったらもっと強くなれると、思う。 You can become stronger if it's scary.
If it's scary, I think you can become stronger. You can become stronger if it's scary.
カッコいいね。お、イエイイエイ！
That's so cool. Oh, yeah, yeah!
深み深い。
Ah, deep meaning.
かっこいい。
That's cool.
キュートアンドクール！
Cute and cool!
ラオラ！
Raora!
みんな！みんなかっこいい！
Everyone! Everyone is cool!
私？いやいやいや。
Me? No, no, no.
チームピンクは非常にクール。
Team Pink is very cool.
ピンクはクールカラー、オッケー？
Pink's a cool color, okay?
ヘイ。
Hey.
ウェル、ハッピーバースデー・トゥ・ユー！
Well, happy birthday to you!
サンキュー・ソウ・マッチ、モリ！
Thank you so much, Mori!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ハッピーバースデー！
ハッピーバースデーな！
Happy birthday, now!
yeah, you can.
You are cool.
Everyone, everyone here is cool.
みんなぐっど。
Everyone is good.
チームピンクは...
Team Pink is...
ベリークール。
very cool.
Pink's a cool color, okay?
Hey.
Well, happy birthday to you, Raora!
Thank you so much, Mori!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations!
Happy birthday!
Happy birthday now!
Yeah.
Thank you for singing "Brave Shine" with me.
It's a very meaningful song, and...
I really appreciate...
to have my Dai-Senpais with me.
Thank you so much!
Yeah, of course, old Senpai!
Old Senpai is here with you.
Well, myself and Towa got to get out of here,
but Raora, you keep on, keep on on, okay?
Okay, I'll do my best!
And we'll see you guys later, okay?
See you guys later!
Bye, everybody!
Peace!
Bye-bye!
白い世界の中では
In a white-colored world,
時間が止まっていくような気がした
It felt as if time had stopped.
いつもしないような表情が
The expression that you don't always show,
その距離が少しだけ愛しかった
I quite loved that very distance.
巻き戻せないと
Your profile when in high spirits,
はしゃいでいるその横顔 抱えていた悩みも
and also when you're a little worried...
君に染まる視界が
My field of vision dyed by you,
かじかんでいく両手が
with both of my numbing hands...
心から願うよ 終わらせたくないんだと
I wish it'll never end with all my heart.
思い出の中にはいつも君の姿
Your figure is always in my memories,
夢のままで 覚えないままで
even in my dreams, even if I don't wake up.
その笑顔が忘れられないや
I can't ever forget that smile.
言葉では足りないようだ
Words are simply not enough.
大人になんてなれないよ
I couldn't even become an adult.
くだらないことばかり
Full of meaningless things,
それでも楽しかった
yet they were enjoyable nonetheless.
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
It'd be nice if this moment can continue for a long time,
なんてさ僕に はにかんでみせるの 泣きそうな声で
I bashfully said somehow in a tearful voice.
新しい世界では
In a new world, I'm sure
きっと心から笑えているのかな
you're laughing from the bottom of your heart.
謝りたいな 見せる顔なんてないよ
I want to apologise yet I can't show my face to you.
僕は君の思う未来のどこにもいないようだ
Seems like I am nowhere to be found in your future.
逃げ出したいような
I don't want to run away,
あの日に戻りたくなるよ
if only we could go back to that day.
振り返ってばかりの人生ならば 諦めよう
If life just keeps on backtracking, then let's just stop trying.
いたいけない祈りも 確かめたい気持ちも
With an innocent prayer and also with ascertained feeling,
今なら言えるだろうか 終わらせたくはないと知る
can I say it now that I know I don't want it to end?
何度でも言うよ 景色は儚げに
I'll say it again and again, the scenery is ephemeral.
足元はおぼつかない 気付けば走り出していたんだ
Before I realised it, I was running with unsteady footsteps.
何度でも言うよ 会いたい言葉など
I'll say it again and again, words like "I want to meet you."
見つかるわけでもない それでもただ信じてみたいから
I don't know if I can find you, but even so I just want to believe it.
思い出の中 君の姿
Your figure in my memories,
夢のままで 覚えないままで
even in my dreams, even if I don't wake up,
変わらないな
remains unchanged.
思い出の中にはいつも君の姿
Your figure in my memories,
夢のままで 覚えないままで
even in my dreams, even if I don't wake up,
その笑顔が忘れられないや
I can't ever forget that smile.
言葉では足りないようだ
Words are simply not enough.
大人になんてなれないよ
I couldn't even become an adult.
くだらないことばかり
Full of meaningless things,
それでも楽しかった
yet they were enjoyable nonetheless.
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
It'd be nice if this moment can continue for a long time,
今度は僕からはにかんでみせるの
this time I'll bashfully show you.
約束しよう
Let's make a promise.
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
If only right now could go on just like this...
今度は僕から見せるの
Next time, I'll be the one to show you.
約束しよう
Let's make a promise.
約束をしよう
世界は終わりを告げようとしている
The world is about to announce its end,
誰にももう止められはしない
and no one can stop it anymore.
――始まる
—It begins.
崩壊の交響曲が鳴り響いて
The symphony of destruction echoes out,
降る雨はまるで涙の音色
and the falling rain is like the tone of tears.
教えて
Tell me,
支配し支配され人達は
ruling and being ruled, do people
いつかその心に憎しみを手に入れ愛することを思い出せず争うの？
someday harbor hatred in their hearts, forgetting how to love and fighting?
この歌が聴こえている 生命ある全ての者よ
This song can be heard, all you living beings,
真実はあなたの胸の中にある
the truth lies within your heart.
嵐の海を行く時も
Even when going through the stormy sea,
決して怯えることのない強さをくれるから
it will give you the strength never to be afraid.
けだし進むほど風は強く
Yet the further we go, the stronger the wind blows,
希望の灯はやつれて消えていく
and the light of hope grows weary and fades away.
「灯りをよこせ」と奪い合い
Snatching from each other with "Give me that light,"
果てに人は殺し合う
people end up killing one another.
涙などとうに枯れて
Tears have long since dried up,
気付いて その目は互いを認めるため
and realizing that those eyes are to recognize one another,
その声は想いを伝えるため
those voices are to convey feelings,
その手は大事な人と繋ぐためにある
and those hands are to connect with someone precious to you.
嵐の海を行く時も
Even when going through the stormy sea,
決して朽ちることのない強さを
the strength that will never decay
くれるから
it will give you.
けれども進むほど風は強く
Yet the further we go, the stronger the wind blows,
希望の灯はやがて消えていく
and the light of hope eventually fades away.
「灯りをよこせ」と奪い合い
Snatching from each other with "Give me that light,"
果てに人は殺し合う
people end up killing one another.
涙などとうに枯れて
Tears have long since dried up,
気付いて その目は互いを認めるため
and realizing that those eyes are to recognize one another,
その声は想いを伝えるため
those voices are to convey feelings,
その手は大事な人と繋ぐためにある
and those hands are to connect with someone precious to you.
傷ついて その目はお互いを見つめるため
Getting hurt, so that those eyes can gaze at one another,
その声は想いを伝えるため その手は大事な人と繋ぐためにあるのに
those voices are to convey feelings, and those hands are to connect with someone precious to you, yet...
この歌が聴こえている
This song can be heard,
世界中の寄り辺なき者よ
all you shelterless souls across the world.
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
Hope lies within your heart.
燃え盛る炎の中でも決して傷つくことのない強さをくれるから
Even amidst the blazing flames, it gives you the strength never to be hurt,
くれるから
it gives you.
その手で守ろうとしたものは愛するものだったのだろうか
Was what you tried to protect with those hands someone you loved?
赤く染まったその手を眺めて
Gazing at those hands dyed in red,
やっと自らがしてきた愚かさをあやまちと認めるその罪を
finally acknowledging the foolishness and mistakes of what you've done as sins,
止めどなく溢れるその涙を知る
and knowing those tears that overflow endlessly.
この歌が聴こえている生命ある全ての者よ
This song can be heard, all you living beings...
世界は終わりを告げようとしている
The world is about to announce its end,
誰にももう止められはしない
and no one can stop it anymore.
始まる
It begins.
崩壊の交響曲が鳴り響いて
The symphony of collapse echoes,
降る雨はまるで涙の音色
and the falling rain is like the timbre of tears.
教えて
Tell me...
支配し支配され人達は
Do people, ruling and ruled,
いつかその心に憎しみを
eventually hold hatred in their hearts,
そして愛することを思い出せず争うの？
and fight, unable to remember how to love?
この歌が聴こえている
Can you hear this song,
生命ある全ての者よ
all living beings?
真実はずっとあなたの胸の中にある
The truth is always inside your heart.
嵐の海を行く時も
Even when crossing the stormy sea,
決して怯えることのない強さを
it gives you the strength never to cower.
けれども進むほど風は強く
Yet, the further you go, the stronger the wind blows,
希望の灯はやがて消えていく
and the light of hope gradually fades away.
「灯りをよこせ」と奪い合い
Snatching away with cries of "Give me the light,"
果てに人は殺し合う
people end up killing each other.
涙などとうに枯れて 気付いて
Tears having long since dried up, realize...
その目は互いを認めるため
Those eyes are for recognizing one another,
その声は想いを伝えるため
that voice is for conveying your feelings,
その手は大事な人と繋ぐためにある
and those hands are for connecting with someone precious.
この歌が聴こえている
Can you hear this song,
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
all shelterless souls across the world?
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
Hope is inside your heart.
燃え盛る篝の中でも
Even amidst the blazing bonfire,
決して傷付くことのない強さをくれるから
it grants you the strength never to be hurt.
その手で守ろうとしたものは
Was what you tried to protect with those hands
愛する者だったのだろうか
someone you loved, I wonder?
紅く染まったその手を観めて
Gazing at your hand dyed in red,
やっと自らしてきた愚かさを
you finally admit the foolishness you've committed
過ちと認めるその罪を
as a mistake, recognizing that sin,
とめどなくあふれるその涙を知る
and knowing the tears that overflow endlessly.
この歌が聴こえている
Can you hear this song,
生命ある全ての者よ
all living beings?
真実はずっとあなたの胸の中にある
The truth is always inside your heart.
嵐の海は静まった
The stormy sea has grown calm,
失ったものは数えきれなくとも
even if the things you lost are countless.
この歌が聴こえている
Can you hear this song,
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
all shelterless souls across the world?
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
Hope is inside your heart.
悲しみの夜を超える時
When overcoming a night of sadness,
必ずあなたはおのれを生きていく強さを持てるから
you will surely possess the strength to live on.
I have to go now.
Thank you so much for watching.
No, not that!
You will continue! Do you know that?
You continue my... live!
Thank you so much everyone! I'm gonna leave you!
No, she won't!
Don't leave me! I'm gonna leave you!
Do you know the dances for the next song?
It's gonna be very fun! You should—
You want me to join? Yeah, yeah, no, you have to do the live now!
I have to do it live now? I'm ready! All right!
I'm ready! Okay, let's go! Let's go!
世界は終わりを告げようとしている
The world is about to announce its end,
誰にももう止められはしない
and no one can stop it anymore.
始まる
It begins.
崩壊の交響曲が鳴り響いて
The symphony of collapse echoes,
降る雨はまるで涙の音色
and the falling rain is like the timbre of tears.
教えて
Tell me...
支配し支配され人達は
Do people, ruling and ruled,
いつかその心に憎しみを
eventually hold hatred in their hearts,
そして愛することを思い出せず争うの？
and fight, unable to remember how to love?
この歌が聴こえている
Can you hear this song,
生命ある全ての者よ
all living beings?
真実はずっとあなたの胸の中にある
The truth is always inside your heart.
嵐の海を行く時も
Even when crossing the stormy sea,
決して怯えることのない強さを
it gives you the strength never to cower.
けれども進むほど風は強く
Yet, the further you go, the stronger the wind blows,
希望の灯はやがて消えていく
and the light of hope gradually fades away.
「灯りをよこせ」と奪い合い
Snatching away with cries of "Give me the light,"
果てに人は殺し合う
people end up killing each other.
涙などとうに枯れて
Tears having long since dried up,
気付いて
realize...
その目は互いを認めるため
Those eyes are for recognizing one another,
その声は想いを伝えるため
that voice is for conveying your feelings,
その手は大事な人と繋ぐためにある
and those hands are for connecting with someone precious.
Oh, no, no, no.
Ah, yeah, because you guys know...
Now you can close the camera.
Now we can close the camera.
No, that is fine.
She said, I am so not done.
I'm going to give you $10.
Absolutely not!
Yeah! Thank you! No!
That hasn't happened! What?
Thank you! No!
Thank you, thank you! It's over!
You know my data for the payment, okay?
Hey, hey, come back!
I don't want to send you money anymore!
Oh, yeah, you got it.
You only have 40 pounds already made.
Fren taxies, okay?
Wait, Fren Taxies, okay?
She's so in-depth with me.
And Fren takes...
This is really bad of her.
My birthday, I decide what I want,
and I decide everything.
Hey, I want $10.
She's going to give me $10.
What should I do?
What should I do? The drama?
Chachinha, please tell her!
I can't, Chachinha, I can't!
Tell her to give you $10!
You look so determined!
You really want this money?
I want it!
Fine!
Here it is.
Just buy yourself some cake and shit.
I'm so done. $40.
I'm so done live on stream.
Oh, my God, it's over.
The mortgage and all that car,
all the insurance.
It's okay, it's okay.
Oh, it's over.
Oh, it's okay. Don't talk about it, let's talk about negative things now.
'Cause today, it's my birthday, we got to celebrate!
How about you bring cake for us?
Yeah.
Where is it, actually?
The cake?
I'm waiting!
I can tell now.
Cake, cake, cake, cake!
It's in the other room!
Cake! It's in the other room!
It's on the table! Don't touch my tail!
Hey, hey, I grabbed your tail.
Come here!
It's kind of easy to get. It's very long.
Listen, listen.
You need to walk, you need to run way faster!
If you want me to do more!
No, no, no, no.
Oh, you don't want? Then I'll grab yours.
Here comes!
It's on! It's on!
I'm grabbing her. It's on!
Taking a bite! Manager, ah!
Oh, Manager-san!
Welcome, my manager, now!
And she's not going to be happy with it.
You know what? I'm going to go and talk to your manager by myself.
No, you cannot talk to my manager!
I spoke to your manager.
I'm done!
No, you're not. Okay, actually we're done.
That was a great workout!
We really did need that cake after all.
Ah, we deserve a cake after all, isn't it?
What's your favorite flavor?
My favorite flavor is...
Ricotta!
Okay!
We have to go now!
We have to go!
There's more to come!
There's so much more!
She has so many surprises for you!
Yay!
You wait for the surprise.
I might know, I might not know.
But I have more surprises.
She does, she does, she does!
So, thank you so much!
Happy birthday, Raora!
Ricotta!
Yay!
Ricotta! Thank you for having me here!
Pingcreatura! Pingcreatura!
Big gray creatura!
Oh, yes!
Yeah, actually talking about clothes, you should put some collars on.
How about some new glasses? Nice and red, you should see them.
I'll show you sometimes soon.
Yeah!
Yay!
Pingcreatura!
More songs!
More songs to go!
Happy birthday!
Yeah, thank you, Rico!
Arigato!
Arigato, ja ne! Ta-ta!
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
言って。
Say it.
あのね、私実は気付いてるの
Hey, I'm actually coming to realize, you know...
ほら、君がいったこと
that thing you said.
あまり考えたいと思えなくて
It didn't seem like I wanted to think about it much,
忘れてたんだけど
and I totally forgot about it, but—
盲目に盲動的に妄想的に生きて
Living blindly, recklessly, full of delusions,
衝動的な焦燥的な消極的なままじゃ
impulsively, impatiently, half-heartedly;
駄目だったんだ
it was really no good.
きっと、人生最後の日を前に思うのだろう
I'm sure that before the final day of my life
全部、全部言い足りなくて惜しいけれど
I didn't get to say everything, everything,
あぁ、いつか人生最後の日
ah, someday on the last day of my life,
君がいないことをもっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、ちゃんと言って
tell me more, more, more, more, properly, that you're not here—
あのね、空が青いってどうやって伝えればいいんだろうね
Hey, how should I convey to you the blueness of the sky, I wonder?
夜の雲が高いのってどうすれば君もわかるんだろう
What should I do so you can also get just how high the clouds at night are?
言って。
Say it.
あのね、私実は分かってるの
You know, I actually already know
もう君が逝ったこと
that you've already passed on.
あのね、わからずやっ て言うんだろうね
You know, you'll probably call me a stubborn blockhead, right?
忘れたいんだけど
I wanna forget, but—
もっとちゃんと言ってよ
More, tell me properly!
忘れないようメモにしてよ
Make a memo so I don't forget!
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかにしようよ
Let's meet 10 o'clock tomorrow at home, or something like that.
牡丹は散っても花だ
Even if the peony petals scatter, it's still a flower.
夏が去っても追慕は切だ
Even if summer is gone, I still cherish those memories earnestly.
言って。
Say it.
あのね、私実は分かってるの
Hey, I've actually realized...
ほら、君が言ったこと
that thing you said.
あまり考えたいと思えなくて
I didn't want to think about it too much,
忘れてたんだけど
and I'd just forgotten about it.
もっと
More,
more,
もっと
ちゃんと言って
say it properly.
あのね、空が青いのって
Hey, how can I convey
どうやって伝えればいいんだろうね
to you how blue the sky is?
雲が高いのってどうすれば君もわかるんだろうね
What should I do so you'll understand?
言って。
Say it.
私実は分かってるの
You know, I actually already know
もう君が言ったこと
that you're already gone.
あのね、わからずやって言うんだろうね
You know, I'm just playing dumb,
忘れたいんだけど
even though I want to forget.
もっとちゃんと言ってよ
Tell me properly,
忘れないようメモにしてよ
make a note of it so I won't forget.
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかしよう
Let's make plans to meet at home at 10 tomorrow.
牡丹は散っても花だ
Peonies are still flowers even if they scatter,
夏が去っても追慕は切だ
and I still yearn for summer even when it's gone.
口に出して
Put it into words,
声に出して
say it out loud.
君が言って
You say it.
そして人生最後の日
And on the last day of my life,
君がみえるのなら
if I'm able to see you,
きっと人生最後の日も愛をうたうのだろう
surely I'll be singing of love.
全部全部無駄じゃなかったっていうから
Saying none of it was ever in vain.
いつか人生最後の日
Someday on the last day of my life,
君がいないことがまだ信じられないけど
I still won't be able to believe you're gone.
もっと
More,
more,
もっと
ちゃんと言って
properly, say it to me.
Thank you so much for being here. ミオ先輩お母さん先輩！
Thank you so much for being here.
I can't believe we sang together!
Yeah, I call her Mio-senpai!
次のゲストは、ニュー先輩と、お母さん先輩です！
And for our next guest,
Happy birthday, Raora!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you so much!
Thank you、来てくれてありがとうございますー！
Thank you so much for coming over!
自己紹介お願いします！
Let me introduce you!
OK！
Okay!
ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオでーす！
I'm Hololive Gamers' Ookami Mio!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆでーす！
I'm Hololive Gamers' Nekomata Okayu!
みお's English Challenge!
Mios English Challenge!
The bro... writing in the concert was beautiful, wasn't it?
It was... It was really beautiful.
おかゆ イングリッシュチャレンジ！
Okayu's English Challenge!
Share and symbolize sincerity and self-acceptance,
and you don't have to try to be strong or try to be perfect.
That's right!
Just accept yourself as you are, and go with the flow and you'll be fine.
Strong, strong, strong cat!
I wanna be a strong big cat!
Not a strong cat!
Thank you, Senpais, for your nice words.
心に響きました。
That really resonated in my heart.
よかった、よかった。
I'm so glad, so glad.
I've got some exciting news for you guys.
It's about the Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026!
So please, Senpai, help me out, okay?
Okay!
お手伝いします！任せて！
I'll help you out! Leave it to me!
ラオーラ・パンテーラ誕生日記念... 記念年は2026！
Raora Panthera Birthday... Anniversary year is 2026!
グッズの... 6月です！
Goods... it's June!
Okay, okay! Let's go, let's go! Guys, take a look here!
B-Day Live Long T-Shirt... Look at this illustration if you like it.
Ski... Oh, so kawaii! Nanda kawaii yo!
I love it... Oh, so cute! Why is it so cute?
This illustration was drawn by Kumiya Sensei.
Thank you so much for making this beautiful art. I'm so happy!
ぐみゃ先生に描いてもらったみたいです！ライブのラオーラもテーマに描いてもらったみたいですね！
It looks like Kumiya Sensei drew it for us! Looks like Raora from the live was also used as a theme!
Okay, so let's take a closer look at the details. First up, this one!
B-Day Live Long T-Shirt... Long sleeves T-shirt! Long sleeves T-shirt!
The features are multi-plug on the back, and there is also a design on the sleeves.
So it's really, really cool for everyday life. So please check it out!
ねえ、袖口とかもついててね、いっぱいデザインが凝ってて可愛いねえ！すごいすごい！
Look, it has cuffs and stuff, and it's filled with detailed designs, so cute! Amazing, amazing!
And next, we have... Ta-da!
Panthera Crossbody Bag... Body bag! Body bag! Body bag! I like it.
And it's a bag designed for everyday use that lets you show off your love for Panthera!
パンテーラがアピールできる普段使いできるバッグになっております！すばらしい！すばらしい！ありがとう！
It's a bag you can use everyday to show off Panthera! Wonderful! Wonderful! Thank you!
Next up is... Ta-da!
Punished Chattini Plushie Keychain... Crying Chattini! Crying Chattini!
Don't stand on that. That's what you deserve. That's what you get!
おおきいチャッティーニ ぬいぐるみキーホルダー。泣き虫チャッティーニ... だからこそウィズ、アナメイジングポーチ！
Big Chattini Plushie Keychain. Crying Chattini... That's why it comes with an amazing pouch!
Next, please! Next, please!
Washing Machine Pouch... Pouch! Perfect!
You can combine them together. So good!
チャッティーニが洗濯機の中に閉じ込められいじゃったみたいです！もうしゅう、もうしゅうチャッティーニ！
It looks like Chattini got trapped inside a washing machine! Oh no, poor Chattini!
ぐるぐるぐる、お洗濯の... ぐるぐる！
Round and round, doing laundry... round and round!
チャッティーニが閉じ込められてるのは、ぬいぐるみ用のマルチポーチですね！すごいかわいい！
Chattini being trapped inside is a multi-pouch for plushies! So cute!
And next up is... Ta-da!
Voice Pack... Situational Voice Pack, "Happy Birthday Raora!"
It's gonna be fun to listen to it, so please check it out! Thank you, thank you!
ラオーラがね、あの収録頑張って収録したボイス、聞いてみてくださいね、皆さんね！お願いします！
Raora worked hard recording this voice pack, so please go listen to it, everyone! Please!
And there is also a bonus for purchasing all the full set. And here it is!
Set Purchase Bonus... Limited Edition Birthday Set: Autographed Instant photo-style card...
And with the message sign,
サイン、サイン、サイン！
sign, sign, sign!
お、こちらは直筆サイン入りのチェキ風ブロマイドカードが、え、フルセットについてきまーす！
Oh, and this hand-signed Cheki-style bromide card comes with the full set!
すごーい！
So cool!
And Cheki-style bro- bromide, br- Englishむずかしー！
And Cheki-style bro- bromide, br- English is so hard!
Englishむずかしかった！チェキカとイングリッシュ！
English was so hard! Cheki-card and English!
With foil-stamped, repro- I can't talk anymore! Signature! Woo!
ちなみにサインは数量限定となっております。
By the way, the signed version is in limited quantity.
よろしくお願いします！
Please check it out!
So here's the full set, please go check it out everyone! Thank you!
そして、こちらはメルちゃんグッズの「Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026」！ありがとうございます〜！
And that was the merchandise for Raora Panthera's Birthday Celebration 2026! Thank you so much!
Neo-senpai! Okayu-senpai! Thank you so much for your support!
You guys worked hard! Did I follow along well? Thank you!
でもすごく楽しかったです！
But we had so much fun!
楽しかった！Yesss! Birthday happy!
It was so fun! Yesss! Birthday happy!
よかったー！
I'm so glad!
Arigato! 嬉しい！
Arigato! I'm so happy!
Alright, now that the merchandise announcement is done,
the next song will be the last one, Saigo!
Last song! 楽しみ！
Last song! I'm excited!
Last song... I'm kind of nervous. Please cheer for me, okay senpais?
Okay, okay! 頑張れ、頑張れ、ラオラ！ファイト、ファイト！ありがとう！
Okay, okay! Do your best! Raora! Fight, fight! Arigato!
じゃあ、Bye-bye! Let's say goodbye! Okay!
Well then, bye-bye! Let's say goodbye! Okay!
Bye-bye!
夢のぬくもりと
With the warmth of a dream,
指先に絵の具の匂い
the scent of paint lingers on my fingertips.
湿ったキャンバスの上には
Upon the damp canvas,
まだ知らない色が息をする
colors yet unknown are beginning to breathe.
All the pieces I picked up
Unravel in my own chest
"It's okay," i whisper softly, saying it back to myself.
迷いも震えも 隠さなくていいから
Doubts and tremors don't need to be hidden away.
この線の全部が 私へ続く
Every single one of these lines leads straight to me.
I'm drawing out my true colors
滲んだ輪郭も
Even the blurred outlines,
淡く、脆く、煌めいて 形になってゆくの
faint, fragile, and shimmering, take shape.
夜明けの面影に 集めた色を重ね
Layering the colors gathered in the shadow of dawn—
Draw it slow, draw it true
夜明けの夢現
In the waking dream of dawn,
微睡に余白の答え
a slumbering answer in the whitespace.
白いページに色が咲いていく
Colors bloom across the white pages,
息づいた景色を描き出す
painting a breathing landscape.
All the colors I held back
Start to gather in the hush
"It's all right," the first light tells me, sending warmth into my heart
願いも希望も 隠さなくていいんだよ
My wishes and hopes don't need to be hidden away either.
ほら、ありのままの 私を描く
Look, I am drawing myself just as I am.
At last, hold my true colors
ほどけた輪郭も
Even the untied outlines,
そっと、ずっと、重なって 私の形になる
softly and forever overlapping into my shape,
静かな始まりに
at the quiet beginning,
目覚めた色を抱いて
holding the awakened colors.
I'm drawing out my true colors
滲んだ輪郭も
even the blurred outlines,
淡く、脆く、煌めいて 形になってゆくの
faintly, fragile, and gleaming into shape,
夜明けの面影を集めた色で描く
painting with the colors gathered from dawn's lingering traces.
Draw it slow, draw it true
la, la, la, la, la, la, la
夢のぬくもりと
With the warmth of a dream,
指先に絵の具の匂い
and the scent of paint on my fingertips,
ありふれた朝の先には
beyond the ordinary morning,
まだ知らない色が溢れてる
colors I don't yet know are overflowing.
Ciao, everyone! I'm still here.
I just wanted to say thank you so, so much for watching my first ever birthday live!
I had so much fun and I hope you had so much fun too!
I worked really, really hard and I'm so happy right now, so thank you chadene, thank you everyone for watching!
見てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for watching!
I have to go now. Bye-bye!
And remember, big cut means big trouble! Ciao!
Ciao, everyone! I have one last message for you all.
Be sure to check out the MB premiere right after this.
Be sure to check out the MV premiere right after this.
And also, my new original song will be releasing on all streaming platforms on May 11th midnight in your local timezone.
So don't miss it out, okay? Also go check out my merch!
Bye-bye-bye! Ciao! Bye-bye!